Dillon Family Papers WLU.Coll.0105
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Dillon Family Papers
1805-1944
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Dillon, Alexander S.
Dillon, Edward
Dillon, Edward Davis
Dillon, Fanny Polk
Dillon, Patrick Henry
WLU.Coll.0105
3 Linear Feet
Ownership and Custodial History
Gift of Mary Unity Dillon, Susan P. Dillon, and Frank C. Dillon, 1979-1981.
Biographical / Historical
the Dillon family resided in Prince Edward and Botetourt counties, Virginia.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the family and personal correspondence (1806-1897), business correspondence, deeds, legal papers, account books (1849-1862) of Dr. Alexander S. Dillon (1813-1870), and family Bible along with ledgers and employee time books of various Dillon limestone companies, especially Edward Dillon and Co. in Botetourt County. Correspondents include Dr. Alexander S. Dillon (1813-1870), Edward Dillon (1835-1897), Edward Davis Dillon (1766-1818), Fanny Polk Dillon, and Patrick Henry Dillon (1804-1862).
Correspondence; Virginia; Medicine; Stone industry and trade; Limestone industry; Deeds; Dillon Family; Edward Dillon and Co.
- Personal Correspondence, 1806-1881 (Box 1, Folder 1-8)
- Business Correspondence, 1869-1898 (Box 2, Folder 9-29)
- Legal and Financial Papers, 1869-1943 (Box 3, Folder 30-50)
- Deeds and Maps, 1810-1941 (Box 4, Folder 51-68)
- Miscellaneous Materials, 1847-1889 (Box 5, Folder 69-78)
  Scope and Contents
  Tis box contains account books,check books,a book of carbon copies of letters, and a photograph.
- Account Books, 1849-1862; 2 Volumes (Box 6)
- Account Book, 1869 (Box 7)
- Account Books, 1879-1883; 2 Volumes (Box 8)
- Ledger Books, 1871-1878; 2 Volumes (Box 9)
- Account Books, 1883-1888; 2 Volumes (Box 10)
- Account Books, 1904-1905; 2 Volumes (Box 11)
- Family Bible, 1791
  This is the Dillon Family bible, dated 1791. It is in a slipcase. It is located on the shelf beside Dillon Family Papers Boxes 9,10,11.
- Time Book, 1907-1908
  Employees' time and pay records from Dillon family businesses.This is a single bound volume located on the shelf beside Dillon Family Papers Boxes 9,10,11.
- Time Book, 1915-1918
  Employees' time and pay records from various Dillon family businesses. This is a single bound volume located on the shelf beside Dillon Family Papers Boxes 9,10,11.